This House Belongs to Her
House of the Witch is a horror, tv movie film directed by Alex Merkin.
A group of high-school kids set out to play a Halloween prank at an abandoned house, but once
they enter they become victims of a demonic witch who has set her wrath upon them.
Dana Brady, played by Emily Bader.
Rachel, played by Michelle Randolph.
Wendy Brady, played by Jules Hartley.
Taylor, played by Arden Belle.
Bicycle Girl, played by Grace Balbo.
Brody, played by Jesse Pepe.
The Witch (stylized as The VVitch, and subtitled A New-England Folktale) is a 2015 folk horror
film written and directed by Robert Eggers in his feature directorial debut.
It stars Anya Taylor-Joy in her feature film debut, alongside Ralph Ineson,
Kate Dickie, Harvey Scrimshaw, Ellie Grainger, and Lucas Dawson.
Set in 1630s New England, the narrative follows a Puritan family who are
preyed upon by an evil force in the woods beyond their farm.
In fear and desperation, they turn upon one another even when the
oldest daughter is suspected of being a witch.
An international co-production of the United States and Canada, the film premiered at the Sundance
Film Festival on January 27, 2015, and was widely released by A24 on February 19, 2016.
It was a critical and financial success, grossing $40 million against a $4 million budget, and is
considered by some to be one of the best horror films of the 2010s and the 21st century.
The film explores themes of witch, halloween, haunted house, prank.
The tone is dark.